RAVEN SHINGLETON



reachravenhere@gmail.com



954-516-4046



linkedin.com/in/raven-s-901b8726a

Summary

Expert in customer service, personnel training, sales, and education. Proficient in IT technical skills. Experience in de-escalation and behavioral science. High level skill in technical training, management, information dissemination. Consistently recognized for professionalism, ability to efficiently manage projects and staff.

Experience



Fair Housing Act Testing Coordinator

National Fair Housing Alliance

Dec 2013 - Mar 2016 (2 years 4 months)

Center for Independent Living - Fair Housing Act, WV

Recruit, train, and educate paid volunteers regarding the Fair Housing Act. Facilitate presentations and meetings to educate tenants and landlords of their rights. Organize and conduct community events and organizational meetings of over 350 attendees. Assist in fundraiser planning, personally networking to raise over \$10,000. Hold meetings with local stakeholders and legislators on accessibility, equal access, diversity, and housing. Gather information on potentially discriminating practices in housing. Conduct preliminary investigations of discrimination complaints. Extensive understanding of ADA and HIPAA guidelines and procedures. Extensive understanding of reasonable accommodations and reasonable modifications. Client advocate and liaison.

Fair Housing Law and Advocacy Training Attendee. National Fair Housing Alliance Training. NAFTA Training.

Vocational Coach

United Cerebral Palsy

Mar 2016 - May 2018 (2 years 3 months)

Provided various levels of instruction to students between the ages of 16-21 transitional skills including vocational training, daily living skills, budgeting, self-care, resumes, and social skills (STEP program). During the summers students were provided on the job training through internships in jobs throughout the community. Completed grant-specific documentation, IEP and 504 documentations, maintained CE training, organized, and hosted community events.

Monongalia Instructor

Monongalia County Schools

Mar 2018 - Jun 2023 (5 years 4 months)

Facilitate a safe, healthy, and productive learning environment for students ages 3-21 years old. Provide full-time day to day instruction for multiple schools over the years as a permanent Autism and Special Education instructor, as well as substitute.

Certifications in Science and English – 2018

Certification for Substitute Nurse Aide- 2022

Pearson Scorer

Pearson

Nov 2022 - Present (9 months)

Score Science and English projects and assessments remotely.



Vocational IT Instructor

Daivergent

Jan 2023 - Present (7 months)

Develop and implement customized remote vocational service programs for neurodivergent adults.

Skills development in

Remote IT software and technologies such as: Google Suite, Microsoft Suite, Adobe Suites,

TeamViewer, SharePoint, Agile,

Scrum, CRM, Trello, Asana, Notion, Slack, Dropbox, and more. Document client progress, billing hours, services, and goals.

Provide instructional and technical support to assist the client in learning the necessary skills required for remote work

success.

Education



Fairmont State University

Bachelor of Science, Sociology



West Virginia University

Master of Science, Data Marketing Communications

Skills

Project Management • Python (Programming Language) • Adobe Creative Suite • Information Technology · Customer Service · Customer Relationship Management (CRM) · Agile Methodologies · Educational Outreach • Data Analysis • Analytical Skills